[dramatic music playing]
[snarling]
[roars]
[giggling]
Oh!
[grunting]
Ha!
[snarls]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[groans]
[all laughing]
[gagging]
[narrator] Madam Dragon ran a school
many moons ago.
She taught young dragons all the things
that dragons need to know.
Zog, the biggest dragon,
was the keenest one by far.
He tried his hardest every day
to win a golden star.
Huh?
[grunts]
[grunting]
[groans]
All the dragons in Year One
were learning how to fly.
Hmm?
[sighs]
[yells]
[chuckles]
High. High!
Way up in the sky.
[gasps]
[laughs]
Huh?
[Madam Dragon gasps]
[gasps]
-[yells]
-[gasps]
[screaming]
[grunts]
Whew! Ha ha!
[sighs]
[laughs]
[gasps]
[giggles]
Hmm. Huh.
[Madam Dragon chuckling]
[Zog gasping]
Ah...
Aw.
[chuckles]
[gasping]
-Ooh.
-[dings]
[giggles]
Now that you've been shown,
you can practise on your own.
[gasps]
[all laughing and cheering]
And you'll all be expert flyers
by the time you're fully grown.
[narrator] Zog went off to practise,
flying fast and free.
He soared and swooped
and looped the loop.
[grunts]
Then crashed into a tree.
[woman] Pearl.
-[Pearl sighs]
-Hmm.
[inhales]
[exhales]
Pearl?
Hmm?
[Zog crying]
Pearl!
[crying continues]
[squeaking]
[narrator] Just then,
a little girl came by.
Oh.
Please don't cry.
[narrator] ...she said.
Perhaps you'd like a...
ooh, a nice, sticky plaster
for your head?
[sniffing]
[rips]
Huh?
Huh.
-What a good idea.
-[narrator] ...said Zog.
[giggles]
And up and off he flew,
his plaster gleaming pinkly
as he zigzagged through the blue.
[dragon] Rarr!
A year went by, and in Year Two,
the dragons learned to roar.
[all roaring]
[sighs] More. More.
Louder, I implore.
[clears throat]
[roars loudly]
[chuckles]
Rarr!
-Rarr!
[long croak]
[clears throat]
Rarr!
[roars loudly]
[Madam Dragon chuckles]
[cheering]
Now that you've been shown,
you can practise on your own,
and you'll all be champion roarers
by the time you're fully grown.
Rarr! Rarr!
[narrator] Zog went off to practise.
[continues roaring]
[panting]
[breathing deeply]
[roars loudly]
He roared with fearsome force.
[roaring]
He kept it up for hours on end.
-[men gasp]
-[horses neigh]
[raspy breath]
But then his throat grew hoarse.
Huh?
[men shouting]
[Zog grunting]
[gasps]
-[Zog panting]
-[men shouting]
[men shouting]
[sighs]
Psst. Hey.
[screams]
[narrator] Just then,
the girl came by again.
[laughs nervously]
[coughs]
Oh, dear.
What rotten luck.
Hmm. Perhaps...
you'd like a nice,
soothing peppermint to suck.
[Pearl chuckles]
[coughs]
-What a good idea!
-[narrator] ...said Zog.
[loud roar]
Rarr!
[laughs]
Oh.
-Then up and off he flew.
-[Pearl laughs]
And breathing fumes of peppermint,
he zigzagged through the blue.
A year went by, and in Year Three,
the dragons learned to blow.
[laughs] No, no.
Breathe out fire, not snow.
[all laughing]
[growls]
[grunting]
[Madam Dragon] Ahem.
[breathing deeply]
Ah!
Now that you've been shown,
you can practise on your own.
You will all be breathing bonfires
by the time you're fully grown.
Hmm. Yeah.
[chuckles]
[gasps]
[narrator] Zog went off to practise.
He blew with all his might.
[chuckles nervously]
[chuckles]
He twirled around in triumph.
And his wingtip caught alight.
[humming]
[gasps softly]
Oh.
Hmm.
[sighs]
[groans]
-[yelling]
-[gasps]
[splash]
[grunting]
[groaning]
[narrator] Just then,
the girl came by again.
-Wha--
-Shh.
-Oh, dear.
-[grunts]
You poor old thing.
[clicks tongue]
Hmm.
Perhaps you'd like a nice stretchy bandage
for your wing.
Oh.
[grunts]
-[whispers] What a good idea.
-[narrator] ...said Zog.
[Pearl chuckles]
[laughs]
[frog croaks]
[narrator] Then up and off he flew,
his bandage flapping wildly
as he zigzagged through the blue.
All the Year Four dragons
were learning...
Can you guess? Yes? Yes?
How to capture a princess.
[grunting]
[laughs]
[grunts]
Ha ha!
[shrieks]
[laughing]
[laughs, cheers]
[sighs]
Now that you've been shown,
you can practise on your own.
You'll need to capture hundreds
by the time you're fully grown.
[narrator] Zog went off to practise.
-Up!
-[all shout]
[shrieks]
He tried...
and tried...
[inhales]
and tried.
-But he simply couldn't manage.
-[screaming]
[grunting]
Ow!
-I'm no good at this!
-[narrator] ...he cried.
-[knocking on door]
-[woman] Pearl!
Pearl!
[sighs]
I'm no good at this.
[grunts]
-[vase rattles]
-[gasps]
-[shatters]
-Oh!
[water dripping]
Hmm.
[hollow knocks]
[grunts]
[woman] Pearl!
[doors banging]
[grunting]
[banging continues]
Ha!
[both grunt]
[gasps]
[woman screams]
[guards shouting]
[all shouting]
[horse snorts]
[sobbing]
I'll never win a golden star.
Hmm.
[narrator] Just then, he saw the girl.
Perhaps...
you'd like to capture me?
My name is Princess Pearl.
[chuckles]
[gasps]
-What a good idea!
-[narrator] ...said Zog.
[guard] Dragon!
There he is! Get him!
Then up and off they flew.
[Pearl] Whoo!
The princess gripping tightly
and they zigzagged through the blue.
[laughs]
[cheers]
Wow.
Hmm.
[snorting]
[both gasp]
Oh.
Ah. Ah!
Our first princess so far.
[chuckles]
[all chuckling]
Congratulations, Zog, my dear.
You've won a golden star.
[gulps]
[gasps]
[Madam Dragon chuckles]
[cheering and laughing]
[narrator] Zog was proud and happy,
and Pearl felt good as well.
[grunts]
[gasps]
She took the dragons' temperatures...
Oh.
and nursed them when they fell.
-Ahh.
Oh.
Hmm.
Ah-ah-ah-choo!
[fire sizzles out]
[gasps]
[squeaking]
A year went by, and in Year Five,
the dragons learned to fight.
[grunting]
[shouting]
[screaming]
[crash]
[groaning]
[cheers]
[horse neighing]
Right.
Right. Here comes a real live knight.
[grunting, armour clattering]
[groans]
[clattering continues]
Good day! My name is Gadabout.
Sir Gadabout the Great.
[squeak]
[squeaking]
[grunting]
I've come to...
[grunts]
rescue Princess Pearl.
Hmm.
I hope I'm not too late.
[narrator] Zog breathed fire
and beat his wings.
You can't!
-She's mine!
-[narrator] ...he roared.
[roars]
Oh, no, she's not!
[narrator] ...yelled Gadabout
and waved his trusty sword.
Ha ha!
The other dragons crowded round
and watched them, all agog.
Who was going to win the fight?
Sir Gadabout or Zog?
-[Gadabout grunts]
-[Zog roaring]
[both groan]
-[inhales sharply]
-[roars]
[grunting]
[screaming]
-[distant grunting]
-Hmm?
[grunting]
[screaming]
-[cheers]
-[laughs]
[grunting]
[narrator] Then Princess Pearl
stepped forward, crying...
Stop!
[screams]
[sighs]
You silly chumps.
The world's already far too full
of cuts and burns and bumps.
[sighs]
Hmm.
[Gadabout chuckles]
Don't rescue me.
I won't go back to being a princess
and prancing around the palace
in a silly, frilly dress.
Oh!
[groans]
I want to be a doctor
and travel here and there,
listening to people's chests
and giving them my care.
-[squeaking]
-[gasps]
[Gadabout chuckles]
Oh.
Me... too!
[narrator] ...exclaimed the knight
and took his helmet off his head.
I'd rather wear a nice,
twisty stethoscope instead.
Ha ha!
Perhaps, Princess,
you'll train me up?
[narrator] And Pearl replied...
Hmm. Uh...
Of course.
[horse snorts]
Hmm.
But I don't see how the two of us
could fit upon your horse.
Flying doctors?
[chuckles]
Ohh! Oh, I'd love to join the crew!
If you'll let me be your ambulance,
then I can carry you.
Bravo! A Dragon Ambulance.
An excellent career!
[narrator] And all the Year Five dragons
gave a loud, resounding cheer.
[all cheering]
[grunting]
[sighs]
[humming]
But what about my trusty steed?
[horse snorts]
Ahh.
[gulps]
I really hope you'll stay.
[horse grunts]
I'll let you be my pupils' pet
and feed you lots of hay.
-What a good idea.
-[narrator] ...said Zog.
[grunting]
Whoa!
[Pearl laughing]
And up and off they flew.
[Pearl cheers]
[Gadabout screams]
[all gasp]
[cheering]
[laughter and cheering]
The Flying Doctors waving
as they zigzagged through the blue.
[dramatic music playing]